Hanchett, Walter Papers 6120
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Photocopies of articles and notes on individuals and Hoover investigation in Coyler case. Frankfurter-Brandeis-Chafee connection.. (Box 16)
  - The 12 Lawyers and National Popular Government League (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Walter Nelles and Tom Emerson Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum Arrests, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    To Brandeis from Anderson 25 March 1920
  - "Holmes and Labor Law", 1936 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Nelles and mermin; NYU Law Quarterly review
  - Nelles, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Harvard Liberal Club versus Skeffington, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Material from William B Wilson Papers
  - 'Fighting Fair", 1981 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Irons; Harvard Law Review, April 1981
  - Frankfurter-Brandeis-Chafee Connection (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Frankfurter-Brandeis-Chafee Connection (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Frankfurter-Brandeis-Chafee Connection, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Harvard Liberal Club, 1919-1920 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Colyer Case, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Colyer Case, 1920-1922 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Colyer Case, 1919-1921 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Colyer Case, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Hoover Investigation of Those Who Opposed Colyer Case, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Lincoln Colcord, Col. House, Woodrow Wilson, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Elizabeth Glendower Evans, 1931-1983 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Davis, Anna N., 1920 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Cosmos Club Anniversary Pamphlet, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - League for Democratic Control, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1920-1991 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Arthur LeSueur, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    April 16, 1920
  - Question of Fanning Admission to Harvard, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Sept. 27 1920
  - West's Report to Mid-1921 on Boston Radical Activities (Box 16, Folder 25)
- Articles and sources on immigration in Cortland and immigrant families. Wickwire industry and family, general data on Ukrain.. (Box 17)
  - Immigration Sources and Articles, 1992-1996 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Russian and English.
  - Immigration Sources and Articles (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Local Sources to Pursue, 1948-1989 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Language and Linguistics in Ukraine and Belorussia (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Summary of History and Activities of Ukraine (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Economy 1976 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Bratush: Ukrainians in Rochester (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Data on Lusitania, 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Thirteenth Annual Report of the Commissioner of Labor, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    March 23 1914
  - Annual report of the Industrial Commissioner, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    April 17, 1916
  - General Data on Ukraine (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Category Divisions (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Wickwire Factory (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Wickwire, 1941-1993 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Wickwire Family, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Other Cortland Industries, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    February 1989
  - Cobako, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Industrial Directories, 1912-1986 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Endicott-Jonson-Binghamton Slavic Community; Immigrants other than Russians, 1919-1987 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Russian Civilization and Ukrainian Autonomy, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    Review of the book by Kohut
  - A Study of A History of Cities and Villages of the Ukrainian SSR, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    Adrian Karmazyn
  - Guide to the papers of Louis Dembitz Brandeis (Box 17, Folder 22)
    University of Louisville
  - For the Welfare of Wage Earners: Immigration Policy and the Labor Department (Box 17, Folder 23)
    Lawrence J. Briggs
  - Felix Frankfurter: An Intimate Portrait, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    The Centennial Exhibition at the Harvard law School; 7 September to 31 December 1982
- Ukrainian history photocopies of essays. Ship list of immigrant arrivals.. (Box 18)
  - The Russian War in Ukraine (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Carpatho-Rusyns (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Moscow-Ukrainian Relations, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    1917-1939; Zottola, GP; August 6 1965
  - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "Ukrainian Farmers in US", 1936 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Halich, Agricultural History, Volume 10, No.1
  - North Dakota History (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - 'Our Slavic Fellow Citizens' (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Balch
  - Xeroxes of Urdanick and Conlun seminar Papers on Binghamton Slavs, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    15 May 1985
  - The Source, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Papers on Genealogical research
  - Ship Lists and Other Sources on Immigrant Arrivals, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Soundex System (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Veterans' Records, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Regarding Ukrainians (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Recent Migration, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Travel to and In Ukraine (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - "Ethnicity and National Identity", 1986 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Wolowyna; (Ukrainians in US)
  - Miscellaneous on Tracking down Ukrainian Relations (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - History and Communism in Ukraine (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - The Term "Ratsap" (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Feminists Despite Themselves, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    Women in Ukrainian Life, 1884-1939
  - Russian Social Democracy in the Underground, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    Ralph Carter Elwood
  - "The Ukrainian Movement in Galicia" (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - "Ukraine and Russia", 1958 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    Konstantyn Kononenko
  - "Ukraine and Russia", 1967 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    Professor Matthew Stachiw
  - Russian-Language Publications on Soviet-Era Ukraine (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Ukrainian in Pictures, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    Yar Slavutych
  - Ukrainian for Beginners, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Sources for Researching Ukrainian Family History, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    John-Paul Himka and Frances A. Swyripa
  - "Labor Immigration in the Atlantic Economies: the European and North American Working Classes During the Period of Industrialization", 1985 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    Hoerder, Dirk
  - Documents Relating to the Russian Revolution (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Documents Concerning Russia and Ukraine in the Early 20th Century (Box 18, Folder 32)
- Photocopies of original documents on legal cases involving Ukrainian workers, including Colyer case/trial.. (Box 19)
  - Stenographic Report of Day 14 of the Colyer Trial in District Court, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    7 May 1920
  - Skeffington v Katzeff 277 Fed 129 Decision of Appeals Court, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Assignment of Errors in Colyer Case, 1920-1921 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Brooks Papers Regarding Colyer Case, Louis Post, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Law Library Holdings on Colyer Case (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Polenberg Comment on Missing Abrams Trial Record, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Fall 1985
  - Katzeff v Colyer Appeals Circuit Report, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    October term, 1920
  - Coyer Case Appeal Appellee's Tried, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    October Term, 1921
  - Coluer Case Appeal Appellant's Brief, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    October Term, 1920
  - Colyer Case Appeal Opinion of the Court, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Colyer Case. District Court Records For Cases # 1833,1835,1837, 1845 at NarsWaltham, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Colyer Case Court of Appeals Record, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    October Term 1920
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Colyer/Skeffington Appeal, Printing of materials Related to Lack of Copy of Original Record, and Opinion of Court Jan 11, 1922
  - Bonder v Johnson, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Other Cases regarding Deportation, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    January 24, 1921
  - ACLU Papers Volume 137 on Massachusetts, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Massachusetts District Court Colyer v Skeffington (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Colyer v Skeffington Anderson Decision, Fed. Reporter Volume 265, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    August to September 1920
  - District Court of Massachusetts Skeffington Cases, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    June 23, 1920
  - "The Communist", 1919 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    Nov 22, 1919
  - "The Communist", 1919 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    September 27, 1919
  - "The Communist", 1919 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    November 15 1919
  - Archival and MSS Collections Special Collections (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - General Reference Aids (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - "The New Labor History", 1955 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    Bornet, The Historian
  - National Union Catalog Pre-1956 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    US House of Immigration and Naturalization
  - Brooks Papers, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    Harvard; 1 June 1981
  - Chafee papers, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    Harvard
  - "A Passionate Intensity", 1977 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    Felix Frankfurter; Harvard Law School Library Exhibits
  - Published Biographies other than Preston's, 1920-1977 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - "Bibliographical Note" (Box 19, Folder 31)
    Preston, from his "Aliens and Dissenters 1903-1933"
  - Worker's National Calendar, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 32)
- Ukrainian maps. Tapes with interviews of Ukrainian workers' relatives, were pulled and placed in media case, they are now boxes 42-69. From Many Roots: Cortland County Chronicles Volume 4.. (Box 20)
  - Maps (Box 20, Folder 1)
    12 Maps of Russia and Ukraine; Russian and English
  - Ataki and Mogiler Podilski Info (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Historic East/West Boundaries Russia/Poland/Austria/Prussia, 1940-1967 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Zakarpatska Oblast, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Vinnitskaia Oblast (Monastirishche, Lipovets) (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Introduction to Map and Gazetteer of Ukraine, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Toronto, 1984
  - Kirovograd and Poskanzer Ukraine, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Poland, 1973-1978 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Ternopol Oblast, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Lvov Area Ternopol (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Kiev Area (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Kiev Oblast Map, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Handout Copies on Kiev Oblast (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Khmelnitskaia Oblast, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Cherkasskaia Oblast (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Lisyanskii Raion (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Cherkaska Oblast (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Kiev/Cherkasskaia Orblasts Border Area (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Brest Oblast Grodnenskaia (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Cassettes, Negatives and Microfilm (Box 20, Folder 20)
    28 cassettes presumable of interviews, 3 sets of negatives of Slavic gravestones, 1986; one box of microfilm with relevant papers attached
- Ukraine Map. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 21)
- Carpatho-Rusyn Settlement, late 1800s. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 25)
- Khmelnitskaya Oblast, 1980s; Western Ukraine and Poland; varios maps of Ukraine, including ethnographic map. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 26)
- Fire insurance maps, Wickwire Plant. Photocopies of news items. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 27)
- Historical Industrial Editions of the Daily Standard, Cortland New York; news clippings, copy of official souvenir of the Wickwire Employees Aid Assoc. 12th annual excursion, Sylvan Beach, Saturday, August 2, 1913.. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 28)
- Cherkassia Oblast.. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 31)
- Khmelnitskaia Oblast.. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 32)
- Kievskaia Oblast and Gubernia (pre-1954).. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 33)
- Kievskaia Oblast (post 1954).. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 34)
- Lvovskaia Oblast. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 35)
- Plan Peterburg, 1914.. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 36)
- Ukraine as a Whole.. Walter Hanchett maps and documents (Box 37)
- L'vov Area Maps (Ukraine) (Box 38, Folder 1)
- Kiev Oblast Map, Kiev Gubernia Map, 1910-1970 (Box 38, Folder 2)
- Ukraine Map (Box 38, Folder 3)
- Grodenskaua, Volynskaia and Podolskaia Gubernias (Box 38, Folder 4)
- Walter Hanchett maps and documents - items from removed mapfolders - bx23, bx 24, bx 29, bx 30 (Box 38)
- Daniluk visit + Repot/Interview after completion of Peaple Mag. Work with them. (Box 39)
- Interview with Jean (Male) N. VanBuskirk, 183 Groton Ave, Cortland, NY (Feb. 11, 1989) (Box 40)
- Barb Woods - Feb. 12, 1989 (Box 41)
- Interview with Veronica Nabywaniak by Mary Dexter, 1979 (Box 42)
- Talk - Mary Lucer - Aug. 8, 1984 (Box 43)
- This + That from CortlandJune 20, 1934-June 23, 1936 (Box 44)
- Len Ralston on Cortland Items - 1976? (Box 45)
- Interview with Mary Kabanuk at her house - July 9, 1985 (Box 46)
- Interview with Mary Kabanuk - July 1, 1985 at her home (Box 47)
- Interview with Mary Kabanuk at her home - Jan. 11, 1985 (Box 48)
- Interview with Mary Kabanuk - conclusion - with help of Helena Za Pletalova - Sept. 18, 1984 (Box 49)
- Interview with Mary Kabanuk, Sept. 11, 1984 (Box 50)
- Interview at her home with Mary Kabanuk, Nov. 27, 1984 (Box 51)
- Interview by W. Hanchett with Mary Kabanuk in her home, Dec. 12, 1984 (Box 52)
- Interview at her home with Mary Kabanuk, Nov. 15, 1984 (Box 53)
- Wickwire House Visit - 2/15/1975 (Box 54)
- Copy of tape which Mary Lucey + Denis Lucey (Box 55)
- Talk with Mary Kabanuk at her home Tuesday, Oct. 16, 1984 (Box 56)
- Conclusion of Julie Barnes Presentation to Soviet State and Society Class, Mar. 27, 1989 (Box 57)
- Interview with Mary Kabanuk at her home, Oct. 24, 1984 (Box 58)
- Interview by W. Hanchett with George Britt (Phoenix, Ariz), July 22, 1985 (Box 59)
- Interview - Anna Kostenko, Jan. 14, 1987 (Box 60)
- Interview with Mary Kabanuk, Oct. 9, 1984 (Box 61)
- Interview with Mary Kabanuk at her home, March 22, 1989 (Box 62)
- Julie Barnes on her visit to Mitaevka Ukraine in Feb. 1989 (Box 63)
- Dup of Hanchett (Box 64)
- Follow up Interview with Viston Chew, Feb. 1, 1985 (Box 65)
- Julie Barnes-Experiences as an Exchange Student in the USSR - 1986, 88, 89 (Box 66)
- Julie Barnes-Experiences as an Exchange Student in the USSR - 1986, 88, 89 (part 2 + 3) (Box 67)
- Interview with Anna Kostenko by Walter Hanchett Assisted by her daughter, Dorothy Barnes (Box 68)
- Interview by W. Hanchett of Mary Kabanuk, Aug. 5, 1985, at her home, no one else present (Box 69)